

Ruslan Ustits

t.me/ustits ustitsruslan@gmail.com github.com/ustits linkedin.com/in/ustits/

Profile

Java/Kotlin backend developer, who likes to take part in all parts of software development cycle. I love agile methodologies, responsible developers and to share experience with others.

Skills

Java, Kotlin, Spring Boot, Kubernetes, Kafka, PostgreSQL, Mentoring, Agile methodologies.

Experience

STAFF SOFTWARE ENGINEER - BACKEND, MTS DIGITAL. MARCH 2022 - CURRENTLYAssisting 4 product teams in turning MTS Investments backend from distributed monolith to something manageable.

Helping engineers:

- Improve their OOP, DDD skills and have fun investigating their business domains
- Grow their architecture skills to bring their software in order
- Be confident interviewers to find new people in their teams

TECH LEAD - BACKEND, SBERBANK. JANUARY 2021 - MARCH 2022

Managed and mentored a team of 7 developers. Experimented with mono -repos and -liths.

- Taught two interns to the level of junior+
- Led the team in migration of Java codebase to Kotlin to fix maintenance problems of reactive frameworks. Got great experience along the way

JAVA DEVELOPER, SBERBANK. MARCH 2018 - JANUARY 2021

Developed search and recommendation systems for Sberbank Online mobile application. Had fun as a scrum master during that time.

- Designed and implemented a system that allows users, using natural language queries, to find what they need
- Built deployment pipelines, acceptance and load testing processes that were used in several teams

JUNIOR JAVA DEVELOPER, STACKSOFT. SEPTEMBER 2016 - FEBRUARY 2018

Maintained billing integration platform. Developed an integration testing framework, wrote more than 100 test cases. That helped to stop testing new integrations only on production.

Education

Russian State University of Oil and Gas. Software Engineer, 2015